Greetings to another Wednesday question
and answer, where we open up with the
Ten Commandments that God commanded the
whole world to keep. Brother Tynsdale.
>> And God spake all these words, saying,
I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage.
Thou shalt have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of any thing that
is in heaven above,
or that is in the earth beneath, or that
is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them.
For I the Lord thy God am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain.
For the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the sabbath day, to keep it
holy.
Six days shalt thou labor, and do all
thy work. But the seventh day is the
sabbath of the Lord thy God.
In it thou shalt not do any work, thou,
nor thy son, nor thy daughter, nor thy
man servant, nor thy maid servant, nor
thy cattle, nor thy stranger that is
within thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the sabbath
day, and hallowed it.
Honor thy father and thy mother,
that thy days may be long upon the land
which the Lord thy God giveth thee.
Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery.
Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
house.
wife,
nor his man servant, nor his maid
servant, nor his ox, nor his ass, nor
anything that is thy neighbor's.
We read Exodus 21:17,
and may the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his word. In Jesus' name we
pray.
Amen.
>> Amen.
So, here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague and long
scripture questions, as well as
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate, we are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So, please be as direct
as possible with your questions, so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. But, let me
introduce to you the family that's on
the panel this evening.
We got brother Julius.
>> Good evening, everybody.
>> Brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Tanzil.
>> Sister Deborah.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Shawn.
>> And we have the guest caller with us,
and I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening?
>> Uh yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Uh M Y M Y asks, "What exactly is a vow
according to the Bible? Is this
something that is promised to be given
to God? Is it a promise of an action?
Can a vow be made before baptism?
>> All right. So, brother Julius, when you
make a vow, can you share some light on
what it all entails?
>> That is the answer to all three of them
is yes, yes, and yes. But, what is a
vow?
What the ask question is what is a vow?
A vow is a solemn
and binding promise to perform an
action.
It's especially to God. Biblically
speaking, you can make a vow to men, but
when you making a vow to God,
you must keep that vow.
You must keep that vow. It is something
that is promised. It is something
for you to perform an action in return
for God to do something for you,
then you make a vow to God, but you got
to be very careful when you vowing a
vow, especially to God and man, but
especially to God.
Ted Z, let's go to Ecclesiastes the
fifth chapter.
Ecclesiastes the fifth chapter.
We're going to read
verse two,
and then we going to skip to verse four.
When you get it, brother, Ecclesiastes 5
and 2. Go ahead.
>> Be not rash with thy mouth,
and let not thy heart be hasty to utter
anything before God.
For God is in heaven,
and thou upon earth, therefore let thy
words be few.
>> Now, skip down to verse four and
continue.
>> When thou vowest a vow unto God, defer
not to pay it.
>> Because you promised, Lord, if you do
this for me,
I promise you
I will do that. I will perform whatever
you are performing towards God. When
thou vows to vow to God, defer not to
pay it. Go ahead.
>> For he hath no pleasure in foods.
>> Uh-huh.
>> So, pay that which thou has vowed.
>> So, now, this is the part that you
really have to be mindful for.
Go ahead.
>> Better is it that thou shouldest not vow
than that thou shouldest vow and not
pay.
>> It is better for you not to vow a vow
than to vow and don't perform the vow.
Okay? Go ahead.
>> Suffer Suffer not thy mouth to cause thy
flesh to sin.
Neither say thou before the angel that
it was an error.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Wherefore should God be angry at thy
voice and destroy the work of thy hands?
>> So, if you ask God to do something for
you and you make a vow to him, you must
keep that vow.
Cuz if you don't, there are prices to
pay. One more place. Let's go to Judges
the 11th chapter.
That's why it's better for you not to
vow
and to vow and don't pay.
Judges 11, my brother. Pay attention.
And when you get it,
this is what
Uh
the Lord This is the man in the days of
Jephthah.
That he vowed a vow to God. If Lord, if
you Let the book talk. Go ahead. Judges
11 and 30. Go ahead.
>> And Jephthah vowed a vow unto the Lord
and said, "If thou shall without fail
deliver the children of Ammon into mine
hands,
then it shall be that whatsoever cometh
forth out of the doors of mine house to
meet me
when I return in peace from the children
of Ammon, shall surely be the Lord's and
I will offer it up for a burnt
offering."
>> Lord, if you give Give me victory over
the Ammonites, I promise you. I promise
you. The first thing that comes through
my doors, I will offer it up for a burnt
offering to you.
Man.
Verse 34, 34 and 35. Go ahead, brother.
>> And Jephthah came to Mizpah unto his
house.
And behold,
his daughter came out to meet him with
timbrels and with dances.
>> His who Who's it His who?
>> His daughter.
>> Because the Lord gave him in the
victory, he returned home in peace
like he asked the Lord. And so now, his
daughter came out to meet him and she
was dancing and she had timbrels and
everything. She was
wonderfully happy to see her father. Go
ahead.
>> And she was his only child.
>> His only child. Go ahead.
>> Besides her, he had neither son nor
daughter.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And it came to pass, when he saw her,
that he rent his clothes and said,
"Alas, my daughter,
thou has brought me very low.
>> No, no, no, she didn't. You brought you
low.
>> Right.
>> You made the vow.
You have brought My daughter, you have
brought me very low. But it was his
fault. Go ahead.
>> And thou art one of them that trouble
me.
I have opened my mouth unto the Lord,
and I cannot go back.
>> So, it came to pass that he had to offer
up his daughter as a burnt offering.
>> Mhm.
>> Be careful when you open your mouth. Be
not rash with your mouth, sisters and
brothers.
Especially you got young brothers that
wants to take the vow of a Nazarite. A
Nazarite cannot have nothing from the
vine. He can't take the Passover. Do not
vow a vow that you cannot pay. That's
all I got, brother Cornell.
You muted.
>> Good light there, brother. Hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next.
Moving on. Ren 64 asks, "What is the
difference between spirituality and
prophetic speaking when people in
churches speak things about a person's
life? Only that person knows and sayings
they receive from God.
>> All right. Spirituality
and prophetic speaking. Brother Drake,
what you say?
>> Yeah.
Well, let's see what the Bible say.
Let's go to 1 Timothy the 4th chapter.
We going to read the first verse there.
1 Timothy 4 and 1. When you get it,
Tenzel, read that.
>> Now, the spirit speaketh expressly that
in the latter times some shall depart
from the faith.
Giving heed to seducing spirits and
doctrines and of devils.
>> So, hey, that the spirit is letting us
know expressly that
in the latter times some will depart
from the faith listening to seducing
spirits
and doctrines of devils. Now, let's go
to 1 John the 4th chapter and we going
to read verse 1 there.
1 John 4 and 1.
Go ahead when you get it, brother.
>> Beloved, believe not every spirit
but try the spirits whether they are of
God.
Because many false prophets are gone out
to the world.
>> So, every spirit that come forth out of
somebody's mouth is not of God.
Sometimes they're seducing spirits and
the book says, but try the spirits
whether they of God or not. But how do
you try the spirits?
You try it by the word of God. Now,
let's go over to
uh 1 Thessalonians 5
and we going to read verses 20 and 21.
1 Thessalonians 5 20 and 21.
When you get it, go ahead, brother.
>> All right,
5.
Despise not prophesying.
And prove all things and hold fast that
which is good.
>> So, don't despise prophesying, but you
got to know where it's coming from. It's
got to be
right here in the word of God, okay?
Because
uh Isaiah 8 tell you that they going to
be those that's going to come with
familiar spirits. Let's go there and
read that. First uh Isaiah 8 and we
going to read verses 19 and 20. Go ahead
when you get it, brother.
>> Isaiah 8 19 and 20.
>> Yes, sir.
>> they shall say unto you, seek unto them
that have familiar spirits and unto
wizards that peep and that mutter,
shall not a people seek unto their God?
For the living to the dead?
Unto the law
and to the testimony. If they speak not
according to this word, it is because
they there is no light in them.
>> So, we should be speaking into according
to the law and the testimony. And the
testimony of Jesus is the spirit of
prophecy. We should be speaking from the
word of God. I got one last place,
Jeremiah 23.
Jeremiah 23 and hit verse 28, brother.
>> The prophet that have a dream,
let him tell a dream.
And he that have my word, let him speak
my word faithfully.
What is the chaff to the wheat? Saith
the Lord.
>> That's right. So,
the one that have a dream, let him tell
a dream. And many of these people that
prophesy are these spiritualists will
tell you they had a dream and they'll
tell a dream. But him that have my word,
let him speak my word faithfully.
What is the wheat to the chaff? Now,
verse 30 and 31, and that is it. Go
ahead.
>> Therefore, behold, I am against the
prophet,
saith the Lord, that steal my words
everyone from his neighbor.
>> Mhm.
>> Behold, I am against the prophet, saith
the Lord, that use their tongues and
say, He said.
>> Mhm.
>> Verse 31.
Behold, I am against them that prophesy
false dreams, saith the Lord.
And do tell them and cause my people to
err by their lies.
>> Mhm.
>> And by their likeness. Yet I sent them
not, nor commanded them. Therefore, they
should not prophesy this people at all,
saith the Lord.
>> So, the bottom line is
look to the word of God for your life
as opposed to all of this
puffed-up, uh, I had a dream and the
Lord showed me and let me tell you what
I'm feeling in my spirit. Look, him that
have a dream, let him tell a dream. And
the book tell you to believe not every
spirit, but try the spirit by the word
of God. So, look to the word of God for
your guidance, and and that will guide
you even to everlasting life. That's all
I got.
>> All right.
Thank you for that. We hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next one.
>> Next one. Be alert asked for you to
explain Isaiah 49, verse 4.
>> Isaiah 49
and verse 4. Let's go there, Tenzel.
It wants some explanation on that
question.
That verse.
Go ahead and let guest caller take it
from there.
>> Isaiah 49 and 4.
So then I said, I have labored in vain.
I have spent my strength for naught.
And in vain, yet surely my judgment is
with the Lord.
And my work with my God.
>> Now, when he say that, it's because
Jesus looking at Israel and he's looking
at this man.
And he's seeing that this man
uh uh
is a prolific sinner. And he figured
that uh
Look, I believe it in vain, but that was
in the affliction of his flesh.
And let's give you an idea what I'm
talking about. First is, he had to die
for this man. Let's go to Matthew the
26th chapter.
And read verse
36.
Then we're going to skip down.
And read a couple more verses. Verse 36
first. Matthew 26 and 36.
>> Then come up Jesus with them into a
place called Gethsemane. And said unto
the to the disciples, sit ye here while
I go and pray yonder.
>> Now, skip down to 30
uh uh
30 uh 7 and see what he 39 and see what
he said.
>> And he went a little further and fell on
his face and prayed, saying,
Oh, my father,
if it be possible, let this cup pass
from me.
Nevertheless, not as I will,
but as thou will.
>> Now,
let's go to St. John 18th chapter
St. John 18:30, he said, let this cup
pass from me, but not my will, but thou
will. Do now when the Pharisees come out
there to get him
and Peter uh
pulled up a sword to protect him. Let's
see what Jesus said.
18, John 18, verses 10 and 11.
>> Then Simon Peter, Peter having a sword
drew it. And smote the high priest's
servant. And cut off his right ear.
The servant's name was Malchus.
Then said Jesus unto Peter, Put up thy
sword into thy sheath.
The cup which my father have given me,
shall I not drink it?
>> So now, he knowing
in his in his in his lamentation, he
knew that he had to do what he had to
do.
But let's see what this cup
represented. Let's go into Psalms 116.
Psalms 116.
We're going to read from verses 1 to 4
first.
>> I love the Lord. Cuz he have heard my
voice and my supplication.
Because he have inclined his ear unto
me.
Therefore will I call upon him as long
as I live.
The sorrows of death compassed me.
And the pains of hell got hold upon me.
And I found trouble and sorrow.
Then called I upon the name of the Lord.
O Lord, I beseech thee,
deliver my soul.
>> Now,
this is Jesus talking about when he's
getting ready to kill him.
And let me show you what else he said.
Skip down to verse 10.
Read from 10
to 14.
>> I believe,
therefore have I spoken.
I was greatly afflicted.
I said in my haste, all men are liars.
What shall I render unto the Lord
for all his benefits to
>> Now he's looking at this. he's a in his
haste, all men are liars. That's why I
say
uh
that they know he he his work is in
vain.
But then he had to go back to say, "What
shall I render to the Lord?" Go ahead.
>> For all his benefits towards me.
I will take the cup of salvation
and call upon the name of the Lord.
And I will pay my vows unto the Lord
now in the presence of all his people.
>> So that cup that he wanted removed
was
him dying.
Cuz he said, "All men are liars." You
know, like
"What am I going to die for these people
for?" That was the flesh
speaking cuz this flesh is the Lord when
Jesus had it on.
>> Right.
>> He said, "But still
I'm going to pay my vow to the Lord and
do what?"
>> And now in the presence of all his
people.
>> Do what was his vow? He's going to take
up the cup of salvation.
Did you read that already?
>> Yep, that was verse 13.
>> See, and that's what the cup that he
wanted removed from his mouth.
Cuz he said, "All men are liars."
What?
Like he told Peter,
he got to take up the cup
that the Lord gave him. And that cup was
his
being crucified. Now, let's go back to
Isaiah.
And we're going to start at fifth
chapter to let you know this is Jesus
talking.
Isaiah
Not Isaiah, I'm sorry.
I mean
not the fifth chapter. Isaiah 49.
Isaiah 49 and we're going to read five
and six.
>> And now, sayeth the Lord, that formed me
from the womb to be a servant.
To bring Jacob Jacob again to him.
Though Israel be not gathered, yet shall
I be glorious in the eyes of the Lord.
And my God shall be my strength.
And he said, "It is a light thing that
thou shouldest be my servant,
to raise up the tribes of Jacob,
and to restore the
the preserve of Israel.
I would also give thee for a light to
the Gentiles,
that thou mayest be my salvation unto
the end of the earth."
>> So, now that's Jesus talking now.
You know,
but the Father sent him to have to die.
He sent him to recover Israel. He said,
"Well, also, I got another task for you.
I'm going to give you the light to the
Gentiles, that my salvation might be to
the end of the earth."
But for a moment there, while he was in
the flesh, he said all his work was in
vain. That was Jesus talking.
But it really wasn't.
He just had to go through that
affliction. That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
any question as we move on to our next
one.
>> Next one, Patricia Mack says, "A family
member wants to know if God created
angels to do his will, why did the devil
disobey God and cause all this
confusion?"
>> All right. If angels supposed to obey,
why did they cause all this confusion?
Brother Julius.
>> Because they were created free moral
agents.
What is the free moral agent? An
individual who has the capacity to
understand the difference between right
and wrong and has the freedom
Again, the freedom to make their own
choices for which they can be held
accountable. In other words, they're
just like us. They're independent
thinkers.
That's why the Lord give us commandments
and he tell us
I set before you life and death,
blessing and curses.
Choose. That mean that you are an
independent thinker for the purpose of
being rewarded for whatever you come up
with and for being punished. So,
let's go to
Isaiah 14th chapter. I have two places.
Isaiah the 14th chapter. All the angels
were created free moral agents. God
don't create robots.
You have a choice.
But what happened to him? His power, his
position, and his pride. Let's read it.
Isaiah the 14th chapter, my brother.
Isaiah 14:10 through and pick this up at
12. When you get it, go ahead. Here's
your answer. Go ahead.
>> How art thou fallen from heaven, O
Lucifer,
the son of the morning!
How art thou cut down to the ground,
which did weaken the nations!
>> His name was Lucifer. Lucifer means
light bringer or truth bringer.
He That's a position. Go ahead.
>> For thou hast said in thine heart, I
will ascend into heaven,
I will exalt my throne above the stars
of God:
I will sit also upon the mount of the
congregation,
>> Come on, T.
>> in the sides of the north: I will ascend
above the heights of the clouds;
I will be like the most high.
>> But that's that But you weren't created
to be like the most high. You were
creating Uh you were created to
minister, to be a servant. But, your
desire your desire This is what he
desired. What is it? Because he got
kicked out? What What What's his
judgment? Go ahead at 15.
>> But, yet thou shall be brought down to
hell,
to the sides of the pit.
>> You going to the lake of fire, which was
created for Satan and the rest of the
angel that were persuaded by him, and
they rebelled against God. One more
place. Let's go to Ezekiel the 28th
chapter.
Ezekiel the 28th chapter.
This guy stood in the presence of the
Lord.
>> Right.
>> And we going to pick this up Ezekiel 28
we going to pick this up at verse 12.
This is It sound like it's talking about
a man, but it's talking about the being
that's behind the man, really Satan the
devil.
Lord kicked him out. Name's not Lucifer.
Now, he's destroyer. Satan.
Go ahead at verse 12, brother.
>> Son of man, take up a lamentation upon
the king of Tyrus,
and say unto him, Thus saith the Lord
God, Thou sealest up the sum, full of
wisdom, and perfect in beauty.
>> Now,
Lucifer, he was full of wisdom, and he
was
one of the most beautiful angel that God
had created. Go ahead at verse 13. This
is not talking about a physical man.
This is really talking about Satan the
devil. The
The one that used to be called Lucifer.
Go ahead.
>> Thou hast been in Eden,
the garden of God.
And every precious stone was thy
covering.
The sardius, topaz, and the diamond,
the beryl, the onyx, and the jasper, the
sapphire, the emerald, and the
carbuncle, and gold. The workmanship of
thy tabrets
and of thy pipes was prepared in thee in
the day that thou was created.
>> Man, he could sing.
All that talent
when he was one of the sons of the sons
of the morning. Go ahead to 14.
>> Thou art the anointed cherub that
covereth.
>> OH, WHAT DID THAT MEAN? That mean that
you are an anointed cherub. You have a
high position.
You stood in the presence of God.
And you are cherubim angel.
Go ahead.
>> And I have set thee so.
Thou was upon the holy mountain of God.
>> Go ahead.
>> Thou has walked up and down in the midst
of the stones of fire.
>> Yes.
>> Thou was perfect in thy ways
from the day that thou was created until
iniquity was found in thee.
>> So now
iniquity, that mean you sinned.
>> Mhm.
>> Continue. Last verse. Go ahead.
>> By the multitude of thy merchandise
they have filled the midst of thee with
violence.
>> Your substance and everything that you
had corrupted you. Go ahead.
>> And thou has sinned.
So therefore, I will cast thee as
profane out of the mountain of God.
And I will destroy thee, oh covering
cherub, from the midst of the stones of
fire.
>> One more.
>> Thy heart was lifted up because of thy
beauty.
Thou has corrupt thy wisdom by reason of
thy brightness.
I will cast thee to the ground. I will
lay thee before kings that they may
behold thee.
>> And you going to see him in the lake of
fire.
And
he was corrupted by his subjects, his
mind, and his pride, and the power that
he had corrupted him. He destroyed
himself because he was a free moral
agent like we are.
We can destroy ourselves by our
behavior. That's all I got, Cornell.
Yeah.
>> That's right, brother. And And also, he
is the father of lies, right?
>> He's the He's the father of lies and
through that he had deceived the whole
world.
Saying that man the liquor fire was not
made for man, it was made for Satan and
his angels.
>> Yeah. All right. Thank you for that.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on.
>> Moving on, Sky Rider asked, "When the
Father's kingdom is established and the
righteous become God and enter to the
kingdom, after all that, I'm curious to
know, what is next? Is that it?
Forever? Or will we get to do stuff?"
>> All right. So, when they talk about
their Father's kingdom,
they're talking about Revelations 21,
right?
And I saw a new heaven and a new earth.
Um
Let's read that chapter
Revelation 21 and read that at 1 and 2.
>> And I saw a new heaven and a new earth.
For the first heaven and the first earth
were passed away.
And there was no more sea.
And I, John, saw the holy city New
Jerusalem coming down from God out of
heaven prepared as a bride adorned for
her husband.
>> All right. So, this is this Father's
kingdom that they're talking about here.
But, turn over quickly to 1 Corinthians
2 and 9. 1 Corinthians 2 and 9 cuz they
asked there, you know,
um they're curious what's next and, you
know, will we be doing stuff? Let's go
to 1 Corinthians 2
and pick it and read that verse 9 for
me. And you asked if if we're going to
Yeah, we'll be doing some stuff, but
here we go right here for an answer to
that. 1 Corinthians 2 and 9. Go ahead,
brother.
>> But, as it is written, "Eye have not
seen nor ear heard
neither have entered into the heart of
man
the things which God have prepared for
them that love him."
So, we don't know.
We don't know. We will see when we all
make it there.
There'll be We'll be doing some stuff.
We just don't know what, but let's just
bag it up with the Old Testament, too.
Isaiah 64 right quick, brother Tinsley.
Isaiah 64
And when you get there, brother, let's
read that one verse four.
Isaiah 64 and four. Go ahead, brother.
But, since the beginning of the world,
men have not heard
nor perceived by the ear
neither have the eye seen
but, oh God, beside thee
what he have prepared for him that
waited for him.
All right. So, we never heard nor
perceived by the ear
neither have eye seen or spoken the
words of all the goodness to come
when we see that new city Jerusalem
coming down. So, the main thing is to
make sure you are there so you don't
miss that show.
And that that's all I got on that.
All right. We hope that answered your
question there, and we're going to move
on, sister Deborah, with a time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:03. Brother Brett
says, "My friend said the disciples were
called Christians as a derogatory word,
like us blacks are called the N-word. Is
that true?
Acts 11:26
and 28 are given."
>> Mhm. Disciples were called Christians as
a derogatory word. Brother Dre, we
definitely need some light on this
question here.
>> No, that's not true, but let's go to
Acts 11 and read verse
25 and 26.
Go ahead when you get it.
>> Then departed Barnabas to Tarsus for to
seek Saul. And when he had found him, he
brought him unto Antioch.
And it came to pass that a whole year
they assembled themselves with the
church
and taught much people.
And the disciples were called Christians
first in Antioch.
>> Yeah, it didn't say it was derogatory
right here. It said they were assembled
a whole year
and they were first called Christians in
Antioch. Now, let's go over to Acts 26
and read verses
28 and 29.
Acts 26:28
and 29.
Go ahead, brother, when you get it.
>> Then Agrippa said unto Paul,
"Almost thou was persuaded me to be a
Christian."
>> Mhm.
>> And Paul said, "But I would to God
that not only thou, but also all that
hear me this day
were both almost and altogether such as
I am, except these bonds."
>> Yeah, King Agrippa, after Paul gave his
testimony as to what happened to him
and and the faith that he had in Christ,
King Agrippa said, "You almost persuaded
me to be a Christian."
And Paul said, "I would to God
that not only you, but also all that
hear me this day
were both almost and altogether such as
I am,
except these bonds." Now, that had
That's not derogatory.
But, let me tell you what the problem
is. And you could you could read this
whole chapter of Acts 26 and it will let
you know
that the problem was the people had a
problem. Let's go to 1 Peter the 2nd
chapter.
1 Peter the 2nd chapter
and let's pick it up at verse 6 there.
1 Peter 2 and 6. Go ahead, brother.
>> Wherefore also it is contained in the
scripture,
behold, I lay in Zion a chief
cornerstone,
elect, precious, and he that believeth
on him shall not be confounded.
>> We're talking about Jesus here. Go
ahead.
>> Unto you therefore which believe
is precious, but unto them which is
disobedient,
the stone which the builder disallowed,
the same is made the head of the corner.
>> So, the builders they disallowed it. And
if you read that whole chapter of Acts,
the 20 the 26 chapter, you find that it
was the chief priests that had a problem
with Jesus. But, read that next verse
right there.
>> And a stone of stumbling,
and a rock of offense,
even to them which stumble at the word,
being disobedient, whereunto also they
were appointed.
>> Israel was appointed to this word.
And he became a stone of stumbling and a
rock of offense to
to them.
But, let's look at one more place. Let's
go to uh
uh let's go to
That was let's go over to
uh
1 Peter 4 now.
1 Peter 4.
We'll look at one more place, here.
First Peter 4:16
- 18. Go ahead, brother, when you get
it.
>> But yet, if any man suffer as a
Christian,
let him not be ashamed.
>> Mhm.
>> But let him glorify God on this behalf.
For the time is come that judgment must
begin at the house of God.
And if that first begin at us,
what shall the end be of them that obey
not the gospel of God?
>> I see that. That's it, right there. So,
if you suffer as a Christian,
let him not be ashamed. Ain't nothing to
be ashamed of.
The one that's offended at him, at the
end, they will be ashamed.
>> Right.
>> If they continue to be a
offended.
For the time is coming of judgment, and
it must begin at the house of God.
>> Right.
>> Go ahead, brother.
>> And if the righteous scarcely be saved,
where shall the ungodly and the sinners
appear?
>> Okay. That's good enough.
That's all I got, bro.
>> All right. Yes, sir, brother Dre. And to
be a Christian is to be Christ-like,
right?
>> That's it.
>> So, if you ain't trying to be
Christ-like, now that's derogatory.
>> That is derogatory, bro.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
And uh we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Next question, Sky Rider asks, "How old
is Ahaziah when he began to reign? Why
does 2 Kings 8:26
have 22 years old, but 2 Chronicles 22:2
have 42 years old?"
>> All right. So, they're looking like they
questioning between 22 and 42, but the
first book they want is 2 Kings, Tenzel,
8:26.
2 Kings 8 and 26. When you get there,
brother, go right ahead and the guest
caller is going to take it from there.
>> At 2 and 20 years old was
Ahaziah
when he began to reign, and he reigned 1
year in Jerusalem, and his mother's name
was Athaliah, the daughter of Omri, king
of Israel.
>> Now, go and read the rest of it about
Ahaziah.
>> Yeah, that would be that Second
Chronicles 22 and 2.
>> Mhm.
>> Second Chronicles 22 and 2.
42 years old was
Ahaziah
when he began to reign, and he reigned 1
year in Jerusalem. His mother's name
also was Athaliah, the daughter of Omri.
>> Okay, that answered that. Ahaziah was 22
years old.
Let me show you why.
We're going to start with his father.
Go to Second Chronicles, the 21st
chapter.
Read verse 1.
Skip down to verse 5.
>> Okay, Second Chronicles 21.
>> 21 and 1. Read that first.
>> Now, Jehoshaphat slept with his father
and was buried with his father in the
city of David.
And Jehoram, his son, reigned in his
stead.
>> Now, skip down to verse 5, because this
this Jehoram
is
Ahaziah's father. Verse 5. Go ahead.
>> And Jehoram was 32 years old when he
began to reign, and he reigned 8 years
in Jerusalem.
>> That means that's 32 and 8, that's 40
years, right?
>> Yep.
>> And
and the only reason they got out of
office is when they died. So the man
died at 40 years old. Skip down the
verse and read 19 and 20.
>> And it came to pass that in process of
time after the end of 2 years, his
bowels fell out by reason of his
sickness.
So he died of sore diseases.
And his people made no burning for him
like the burning of his father.
So 30 and 2 years old was he when he
began to reign.
And he reigned in Jerusalem 8 years and
departed without being desired.
Howbeit they buried him in the city of
David. But not in the sepulchers of the
kings.
>> Okay now, one of the place second
Chronicles 22:1 and 2.
>> And then the inhabitants of Jerusalem
made Ahaziah his youngest son king in
his stead.
For the band of men that came with the
Arabians to the camp had slain all the
elders. So Ahaziah
Ahaziah
the son of Jehoram, king of Judah
reigned.
42 years old was Ahaziah when he began
to reign.
And he reigned 1 year in Jerusalem. His
mother's name also was Athaliah, the
daughter of Omri.
>> So so the answer is he was 22 years old
cuz his father Jehoram died when he was
40.
So how can a 40-year-old man that died
in 40 years have a 42-year-old son?
So the answer to that is
Ahaziah was 22 years old when he began
to reign. Okay?
>> Mhm.
All right.
All right. Good question. Hope you seen
that light as we move on to our next
one.
>> Next one, Britt Brat asked, "Are people
Are people who only use the New
Testament in their daily lives headed to
the lake of fire?"
>> All right, brother Dre. If you only in
that New Testament, are you headed to
the lake of fire?
>> That's a judgment call for God, but I
will tell you this much, they are
lacking.
Okay? They do not have the law and the
testimony. And if they don't speak
according to that, we just read that in
Isaiah 8. Go read it one more time.
Isaiah 8:19 and 20, brother.
>> Isaiah 8:
>> 19 and 20.
>> Okay.
>> I just read 20. 20.
To the law and to the testimony, they
speak not according to this word, it is
because there is no light in them.
>> So, they don't have the whole story. In
fact, let's go over to Matthew 24 now.
Matthew 24
and we going read verses
3 to 5 because there's a lot of people
that tell you all you need to be is a
New Testament Christian.
And if you a New Testament Christian,
you're lacking. You're missing
something. So, Matthew 25 24:3 to 5. Go
ahead, brother.
>> And as he sat upon the Mount of Olives,
the disciples came unto him privately,
saying,
"But tell us, when shall these things
be? And what shall be the sign of thy
coming and of the end of the world?"
>> Mhm.
>> And Jesus answered and said unto them,
Take heed that no man deceive you.
For many shall come in my name, saying,
I am Christ. And shall deceive many.
>> And that is a lot of what's going on
right now. They holler Christ,
but they are deceiving people. Skip down
to verse 15.
>> And you shall therefore And when you
shall therefore see
the abomination of desolation,
spoken of by Daniel the prophet,
stand in the holy place.
Whoso readeth, let him understand.
>> So, if you don't have Daniel the prophet
in your New Testament Bible,
how you going
understand? How you going read and
understand? You can't.
You cannot do it. Now, let's go over to
Matthew 13,
and I'mma land with uh verses 51 and 52.
51 and 52.
Go ahead and read it when you get there,
brother.
>> And Jesus said unto them, Have ye
understood all these things?
And they said unto him, Yeah, Lord.
>> Mhm.
>> Then said he unto them,
Therefore every scribe, which is
instructed unto the kingdom of heaven,
is likened to a man that is an
householder,
which bringeth forth out of his treasure
things new and old.
>> And you need both,
new and old.
So, don't let nobody tell you that that
all you need is the New Testament, or
all you need is the Old Testament. The
law and the testimony. That's all I got.
>> Yeah, you right, Drake. If they tell me
I'm reading the New Testament only,
that's
that's 39 books. I have an old that you
have totally deleted out of God's
program.
>> Mhm.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So, please read both books, old and new,
like brother Dre said. We hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next.
>> Moving on. Philosopher B asked, "In
Deuteronomy 5:23,
it references Exodus 19, where the Lord
spoke to the people. I'm wanting to know
if it's the angel of the Lord or was it
Jesus that they heard and seen in the
clouds?"
>> All right, brother Julius, who was it
speaking?
>> Let's forget us. Let's see what the book
say. Let's go to that Deuteronomy 5.
They gave Deuteronomy 5 and 23, but they
read past the answer.
Deuteronomy 5, this time, Kanzel, we
going to start at verse 22. Deuteronomy
5 and 22. Go ahead and read, and then we
going to go back to the Exodus 19th
chapter. Go ahead and read.
>> These words the Lord spake unto all your
assemblies in the mouth of the midst of
the fire.
>> Who Who did it?
>> The Lord.
>> Go ahead.
>> Of the clouds and of the thick darkness
with a great voice. And he added no
more.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And he wrote them in two tables of
stones and delivered them unto me.
>> And they delivered them unto them. Go
ahead. 23 and 24, continue.
>> And it came to pass when you heard the
voice out of the midst of the darkness,
for the mountain did burn with fire,
that you came near unto me,
even all the heads of your tribes and
your elders.
And you said, "Behold,
the Lord our God has showed us his glory
and his greatness.
And we have heard his voice out out the
midst of the fire.
We have seen this day that God do talk
with man, and he lived.
>> So, they heard the voice, but they never
saw the face.
Because he came down in the smoking in
the mountain and with a powerful voice
that scared them to death. Let's see.
Let's look at it. Exodus the 19th
chapter.
Back up to Exodus the 19th chapter, 10
jail.
And we going to read 9 to 11 and skip.
Exodus 19 and 9. Exodus 19 and 9. Go
ahead.
>> And the Lord said unto Moses, "Lo, I
come unto thee in the thick cloud,
>> No, no, no. I'm going to send my angel.
>> Uh
No.
The Lord said unto Moses, "I come unto
thee in the thick cloud,
>> Uh-huh.
>> that the people may hear when I speak
with thee,
and believe thee forever."
And Moses told the words of the people
unto the Lord.
And the Lord said unto Moses, "Go unto
the people, and sanctify them today and
tomorrow,
>> Uh-huh.
>> and let them wash their clothes,
and be ready against the third day.
For the third day the Lord will come
down in the sight of all the people upon
Mount Sinai."
>> Skip down to verse 16. The Lord is going
to come down himself. Verse 16. Go
ahead.
>> And it came to pass on the third day in
the morning that there were thunderings
and lightnings and a thick cloud upon
the mount.
The voice of the trumpet exceeding loud,
so that all the people that was in the
camp trembled.
>> Skip down to verse 19 and 20 and we'll
be done. Go ahead.
>> And when the voice of the trumpet
sounded longer and waxed louder and
louder,
Moses spake.
God answered him by a voice.
And the Lord came down upon Mount Sinai,
on the top of the mount.
And the Lord called unto Moses
up to the top of the mount, and Moses
went up.
>> So, that was the Lord himself coming
down and talked to the people with a
great voice, earthquake shaking,
mountain shaking, thunder, pillars of
smoke, scared the people to death.
They heard the voice, they never saw the
face. So, that was the Lord, not an
angel in this context. And it's going to
be like that when the Lord come back uh
the second time to this earth, the
trumpet going wax louder and louder and
louder, the seventh trumpet, and the
Lord himself going to come back to this
earth. That's all I got.
>> Yep. And straighten it out.
All right. Well, hope that answered your
question.
>> going to say, "Uh-huh, hide us from the
face of him that sit up on the throne."
They going to see him again this time.
Eyeball to eyeball. Go ahead, brothers.
>> Yep.
All right. Well, hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next.
>> Moving on, philosophy also asks, "In
Deuteronomy 12:15,
what does this mean? Does it mean that
they were allowed to eat unclean animals
as well?"
>> No. First of all, let me start off with
the
"Does it mean they were allowed to eat
unclean animals as well?" No. Lord has a
dietary law that say you have to eat
only the things that he said you shall
eat, and then he got a list of the
things that you shall not eat. Well,
let's go read what you put in there,
which is Deuteronomy 12 and 15.
Let's go there.
Deuteronomy 12 and 15. And brother
Tenzel, before you read it, when we see
unclean in here, I want them to consider
that we are talking about people here
and not animals. So, go ahead, brother,
pick it up at that Deuteronomy 12 and
15, cuz this is people when the Lord is
talking about unclean and clean in this
verse. Go ahead.
>> Notwithstanding, thou mayest kill and
eat flesh in all thy gates.
Then whatsoever thy soul lusteth after,
according to the blessing of the Lord
thy God
which he hath given thee.
The unclean and the clean may eat
thereof
as of the roebuck and as of the hart.
>> So here where it says, "Notwithstanding,
thou mayest kill and eat flesh in all
thy gates whatsoever thy soul lusteth
after." But those that have the word of
God only lust after the food that God
say that we can eat.
So when it talks about the unclean, "The
Lord thy God which he hath given thee,
the unclean The unclean people as well
as the clean people may eat thereof as
of the roebuck and as the hart." So this
is talking about people here.
But let's go and back up the dietary
law. Let's go in that Leviticus 11.
Leviticus 11. It show that the Lord got
a dietary law and he tell you what you
can eat and what you cannot eat. And it
behooves everybody who have an ear to
hear
to do what thus says the Lord and only
eat what he say you can eat and stay
away from what he say you cannot.
Leviticus 11
and let's pick it up
at that verse 1
and go ahead, my brother, and let's see
cuz this is the Lord as he spake unto
Moses and to Aaron.
Go ahead.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses and unto
Aaron, saying unto them,
"Speak unto the children of Israel,
saying, These are the beasts which ye
shall eat among all the beasts that are
on the earth.
>> So the Lord say, "This is what you may
eat out of all the beasts that's on the
earth." Go ahead.
>> Whatsoever part of the hoof and is
cloven footed and cheweth of cud among
the beasts, that shall ye eat.
>> So, you should read this all on your
own, this whole chapter, but we just
going to stick here and there. Skip down
because this is a popular meat that
people eat that the Lord said, "Don't
eat it." Verse seven.
>> And the swine, though it divided the
hoof, and be cloven-footed,
yet he cheweth not the cud. He is
unclean to you.
>> The Lord said he don't want you eating
the pig, no matter how popular it is. He
do not want you to eat it. He created
it, and he know
what he wants us to eat, and what he
does not want us to eat. Skip down,
brother, to verse
43, because when you eat the thing, go
ahead, Gas Power.
>> Yes, sir.
You already answered the question.
Question was
uh uh
could you eat clean and unclean, and you
you explained to him that he was saying
the unclean and clean people
eating of it.
The question is answered.
>> Oh, okay. Well, very good.
>> And and then you can pick that up uh
Deuteronomy 15 and 22. It actually says
it.
All right.
Yeah. Thou shalt eat of it.
>> The answer the answer
was given in the question.
Uh all right. We just read what the what
it says.
>> All right.
Okay.
Don't tell me we over
>> over answer, and people
get confused of what the question was.
It's been answered.
>> Okay. We don't want no confusion. We
here to dismantle confusion.
>> All right.
>> All right. We hope that answered your
question there as we
keep moving.
>> Yes, let's keep moving on. Mark
Kimbrough asked, are there any
are there any version
are there any verse on how to correctly
ask for healing?
>> It has to be brother Julius many sick
people as we got.
>> Absolutely there is. Abs- abs-
absolutely there is.
First of all, you got to have faith in
God and you got to be right.
You want to be right.
Let's go to let's go to two perfect
examples.
Let's go to Isaiah 38th chapter.
We're going to read verses 1 to 5. This
is Hezekiah, king of Judah, a good king.
And he's he obeyed God, he believed in
God, but he got sick unto death.
Isaiah 38
and 1 to 5. Let's go to him, Tenzel.
>> In those days was Hezekiah sick unto
death.
And Isaiah the prophet, the son of Amos,
came unto him and said unto him,
Thus said the Lord, Set thy house in
order, for thou shalt die, and not live.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Hezekiah turned his face toward the wall
and prayed unto the Lord.
>> Wait a minute. He did what? He prayed
unto the Lord.
He prayed unto the Lord, and then he
threw up some of his the good work that
he had done?
And well, go ahead.
>> And said, Remember me now, O Lord,
I beseech thee, how I have walked before
thee in truth and with a perfect heart.
>> That's great right there. With truth and
with with a a righteous heart. Go ahead.
>> And have done that which is good in thy
sight.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And Hezekiah wept sore.
>> Then what happened?
>> Then came the word of the Lord to Isaiah
saying,
Go and say to Hezekiah, Thus saith the
Lord,
the God of David thy father, I have
heard thy prayer,
I have seen thy tears.
Behold, I will add unto thy days 15
years.
>> He prayed.
He was righteous, and the Lord heard the
prayer of the righteous, sisters and
brothers.
And he gave him 15 more years. My last
place, James, the fifth chapter.
James, chapter five.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And we going to read 13 to 16.
Cuz he don't change.
James 5:13, go ahead, brother.
>> Is any among you afflicted? Let him
pray.
Is any merry? Let him sing psalms.
>> Yes.
>> Is any sick among you? Let him call for
the elders of the church, and let them
pray over him,
anointing him with oil in the name of
the Lord.
>> And that's what you get. That's the
protocol that you could follow right
there. You call for the elders of the
church, and you could pray and let them
pray over you, let them anoint you. We
do that all the time in Israel of God,
and we pray for healing. Go ahead.
>> And the prayer of faith shall save the
sick.
>> They got to have faith. You got to
believe. Go ahead.
>> And the Lord shall raise him up.
And if he have committed sins, they
shall be forgiven him.
>> You got it. You can ask for forgiveness
of those sins. Go ahead.
>> Confess your faults one to another, and
pray one for another, that ye may be
healed.
>> That you may be healed.
>> The effectual
>> maybe sometimes we got to confess them
faults, and sometimes we got to
acknowledge our transgression, and then
the Lord can hear. Go ahead.
>> The effectual fervent prayer of a
righteous man availeth much.
>> He gave you Hezekiah's a righteous man.
I've been right in your eyes. I've done
this, and God don't change.
I'm a witness that he don't change. I
had the COVID. I prayed to the Lord,
take this away from me and my daughter.
I sit before you a witness in Jesus
name. That's all I got.
>> All right.
Yes, sir. Let's keep it moving sister
Deborah with the time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:30. Kyle B. Jr. asks,
"What does Matthew 20:16
mean?"
>> All right, we asking in question about
that Matthew 20:16. Let's go there
Tenzel.
>> Matthew 20:16.
>> Yeah, dealing with the first and the
last. And the guest caller take it from
there.
>> So, the last shall be first and the
first last. For many be called, but few
chosen.
>> Okay.
Go to Matthew 21 read verse
28 to 32.
>> But, what think ye? A certain man had
two sons.
And he came to the first and said, "Son,
go work today in my vineyard."
And he answered and said, "I will not."
But, afterwards he repented and went.
And he came to the second and said
likewise. And he answered and said,
"I go, sir." And went not.
Whether of them twain did the will of
his father?
And they said unto him, "The first." And
Jesus said unto them, "Verily I say unto
you, that the publicans and the harlots
go into the kingdom of God before you."
>> Now, he let you know that look,
the son that says,
"I will not." That represent the
publicans and the harlots and the
sinners.
And the ones that
I will and didn't go.
That represents the people that supposed
to be servants of God. What worship is
that?
>> That was in the 31.
>> Go ahead. Read verse two.
>> For John came unto you in the way of
righteousness.
And you believed him not.
But the publicans and the harlots
believed him.
And you when you had
seen it, repented not afterwards that
you might believe him.
>> So now, he was talking to the Pharisees,
the people that supposed to be the
servants of God and believe.
John the Baptist came, they didn't
believe.
But the publicans and the harlots and
the street people believed and they
repented.
>> Right.
>> So now,
through the ones that it looked to be
first are the people that supposed to be
serving God.
But then, they going to end up being
last.
Read Matthew the 7th chapter and read
verse 21 to 23.
>> Matthew 7 and 23?
>> 21 to 23.
>> Not everyone that says unto me, "Lord,
Lord, shall enter into the kingdom of
heaven.
But he that doeth the will of my Father
which is in heaven,
the many will say to me in that day,
"Lord, Lord,
have we not prophesied in thy name?
And in thy name have cast out devils.
And in thy name done many wonderful
works."
And then I will profess unto them,
"I never knew you.
Depart from me, ye that worketh
iniquity."
>> Now, these people tell me they did all
this stuff in the Lord's name. They
supposed to be the servants of God.
These people don't talk like that.
>> Right.
>> But then, once they get through doing
all of the talking, God said to prophesy
me.
I
work over there, but I never knew you
because they did all the talk, but they
didn't do his will. What verse was that?
>> That was in 23.
>> Okay, let's go to the last place.
Matthew 22.
Read verses 1 and 2.
Then we're going to skip.
>> And Jesus answered and spake unto them
again by parable parables and said,
"The kingdom of heaven is like unto a
certain king,
which made a marriage for his son."
>> Now skip down to verse 10.
>> "And those servants went out into the
highways and gathered together all as
many as they found, both bad and good.
And the wedding was furnished with
guests.
And when the king came in to see the
guests, he saw that there was a man
which has not on a a wedding garment.
He said unto him, "Friend,
how comes thou in hither not having a
wedding garment?"
And he was speechless.
Then said the king to the servants,
"Bind him head and foot and take him
away. Cast him into outer darkness. And
there shall be weeping and gnashing of
teeth.
For many are called,
but few are chosen."
>> So, now, there's a lot of people that
are called by the word of God. They come
in and they start, but then, they don't
keep his laws and his statutes. They
confess to him with their lips.
And so, but the one and so, that mean
that you confessing with your lip, but
you ain't doing right. So,
so the Lord the
attire for the righteous, the clothing
for the righteous compared to linen.
Clean, white, and clean. That's the
righteousness of the saints. So, now you
might be called, but if you don't keep
these laws and these statutes,
you are not going to be chosen. You're
going to end up in the lake of fire. So,
many are called,
but few are chosen. Like this guy.
And many going to be many that people
look up on this first are the people
that's running around in church every
Sunday,
and but they ain't keeping the
commandments. But you get street people
once they find out about it, they stop
doing it.
You know, just like it was in
Jericho.
All of Jericho fell to Joshua and them.
The only one that was saved was a harlot
and her family.
>> Rehab.
>> That's right, because she believed the
spies
that Israel that Moses sent. So,
she was last being a harlot. She was
last in in
Jericho.
And the people that were first of the
religions and the kings and all them,
they was first.
So, who got it who So, who was saved?
The harlot and her household.
That's what it mean. The first of the
people that confessed to be
to serve God and don't,
and the last of the people that don't
confess nothing, but when they find out
what the truth is, they find out about
God's law, and they start walking in it,
then they were the first the last.
Sinners and the publicans
and the prostitutes, but they repented.
So, they became first.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
We'll continue to move on to our next
question.
>> Next question, June Green asks, "If a
family member is getting married and
it's on Saturday, can I attend the
wedding and meal? And if it was on a
Friday, could I attend the evening meal
as it goes into the Sabbath?"
>> All right, look like we talking about a
wedding here. Guess call.
>> Well, the wedding itself ain't no
problem with having a wedding because
the Lord did that, but you can't go
through the festival.
Do not. They going to throw a wedding
and then they going to cook some food on
the Sabbath day and you going to eat it?
No.
And if you have a wedding on Friday
and then
uh they wait until they and then they go
into the Sabbath day cooking food, you
should eat it? No. Cuz what did the Lord
say? He wants you to keep his Sabbath
day holy. Go in Isaiah 58.
Read verses 13 and 14.
>> If thou turn away thy foot from the
Sabbath doing thy pleasure on my holy
day and call the Sabbath a delight
the holy of the Lord honorable and shall
honor him not doing thy
own ways nor finding thy own pleasure
nor speaking thy own words
then shall thou delight thyself in the
Lord
and I will cause thee to ride upon the
high places of the earth
and feed thee with the heritage of Jacob
thy father
for the mouth of the Lord has spoken it.
>> So, now, you supposed to keep the
Sabbath day holy. Marriage is a holy
thing. Like sometime we married I
married people right there on the stage
on the Sabbath day.
But then
they can't go and sit down and start
eating and getting off on in all kind of
festivals and
uh uh
talking a whole lot of stuff that should
be talked on the Sabbath day.
Do you want to answer that is?
You can get married, but you cannot sit
down and eat and take part of the
festival. That's all I have to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next
question.
>> Next one,
says, "I know the tribulation period
will be 3 and 1/2 years, but how many
months will God's wrath be?"
>> All right, that's good you know how long
the tribulation will be.
What about the wrath?
The months of God's wrath. Yes, caller.
>> I don't know.
Not written.
Only part is written is one uh uh uh
one uh uh uh
set of the the witnesses go uh uh
come into the east for so many months.
That's about it.
All I know is it'll be over when the
seventh trumpet is blown.
Other than that, I don't know.
>> All right.
Our next question with the time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:41. Siamaru
uh Israel also asks,
"If Sunday church worship is dedicated
to a sun god, should musicians that are
in the truth be participating or playing
for them in their churches?"
>> Yes, caller.
>> Answer is no.
So, that
>> All right.
Okay.
We're going to
Sister Deborah, we going now into new
territory.
>> Yes, we are.
Uh we are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, November the 5th, 2025.
Detroit Price asks,
"In Exodus 12:18
and in Ezekiel 45:21,
how do we get eight days from the 14th
day to the 21st day of the month?"
>> All right.
Uh 80 said Exodus 12:18?
>> Yes.
>> And the And the second one is Ezekiel
45?
>> 45 and verse 21.
>> And the question again. All right, 10
days
12.
>> Yes, how do we get eight days from the
14th day to an
to the 21st day of the month?
>> All right, Exodus
12:18.
And then we're going to
open it up. I'd like the guest caller
will have first crack at that one.
Exodus 12:18.
>> In the first month of the 14th day of
the month at evening,
you shall eat unleavened bread until the
1 and 20th day of the month at evening.
>> So now,
count from 20 from 14 to 21. So, how
many days is that?
>> Seven.
>> Huh?
>> Two days.
>> How many?
>> You said 21 minus 14, right?
>> Yeah, from from from the 14th to 21st,
how many days?
>> 7 days.
>> 7 7 days.
>> That's right. So, that means when the
sun go down on the 14th day,
then you start count the 7 days.
So, it say from evening to evening.
From
from 14 to 15 is what how many days?
See what you do?
>> What 1 day?
>> Huh? 1 day. From 15
to 16 is what?
>> 2
>> 2. 16 to 17 is what?
>> 3
>> 17 to 18 is what?
>> 4
>> 18 to 19 is what?
>> 5
>> 19 to 20 is what?
>> 6
>> And from 20 to 21 is what?
>> 7
>> 7 7 days.
>> So, when the sun go down on the 14th
day,
that starts
and
it begin the 15th. The 15th day is the
first day of the feast of unleavened
bread.
>> Mhm.
>> So, the 14th is the Passover.
Now, what was the other question?
>> Over there.
>> Um that
It It's the same question. He just gave
a scripture, Ezekiel 45 verse 21.
>> So, he said how many how what he say
about that now?
>> How do we get 8 days from the 14th day
to the 21st day of a month?
>> You don't get 8 days. You get 7 days.
All you got to do is do the math.
>> Yeah, and then
>> When the sun go down on the 14th
And and and
and between and uh uh
It starts to count. 14 and 15, you don't
count on the day, you count in between
because it's from evening to evening.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yeah. All right.
So, we hope that answered your question.
Next one.
>> Next one. Malik Banks says, "Following a
funeral service where where I have come
into physical contact with a deceased,
what are the appropriate practices or
observances
uncleanness?"
>> Okay. They said something about
following a
Can you repeat that question?
>> Yeah, following a funeral service where
I have come into physical contact with a
deceased. What are the appropriate
practices or observances
during the 7-day period of uncleanness?
>> All right. Well, we can we can kick it
off in Numbers 19. Open it up to the
panel, also.
Let's go to Numbers 19.
It talks about when somebody dies in a
tent
or even if you come into
like you said, physical contact, which
makes you unclean for 7 days.
Read that verse 14, 15
and uh
16.
>> This is the law when a man dieth in the
tent, all that come into the tent, and
all that is in the tent shall be unclean
seven days.
Every open vessel which have no covering
bound upon that is unclean.
And whatsoever touches one that is slain
with the sword in the open field or dead
body or bone of a man or grave shall be
unclean seven days.
All right.
So, they said they came in a physical
contact actually with that body, so they
unclean for seven days.
And they want to know, Deborah, what
what do they need to do?
>> What? Yeah, what is the appropriate
practice or what should they do while
they're observing during that seven-day
period of uncleanness?
>> Just don't go in and
just don't deal with anything that's
holy.
But nowadays, you got a problem. There
ain't nothing holy nowadays. But when
you're Israel was a nation, then you had
to separate yourself. They had a special
place to
uh uh
until the seven days over which you
couldn't go to the temple
or nothing.
Just stay away from everything until you
was until the seven days was over with.
And then once that was over with, then
you had to get purified by the ashes
and and the solution made from the red
heifer. But since Jesus died, you don't
have to do that. You just stay away from
everything that's holy for seven days.
That's it.
>> That's it.
>> We don't have no waters of purification
anymore, none of that.
>> Right.
>> Uh-huh.
Jesus took care of that.
>> All right.
We're going to move to our next question
as time is ticking.
>> Yeah, Shaniqua Akujobi says, "I know
secular music isn't good since it
doesn't align with the word.
What about Christian rap hip-hop?
They have similar rhythms as secular
rap. Is it wrong to listen to if the
content is positive?
>> Will somebody go and read what sin is?
>> All right. I'm going to go there 1 John
3 and 4. Can I tell
>> 1 John 3
and we're going to pick it up at verse
4.
Whosoever committeth sin transgresseth
also the law. For sin is the
transgression
of the law.
>> So now anything beyond that
if you don't break the law
then then why is it you get secular
music
or anything else? You can call sin. Sin
is the transgression of the law. See,
this is what's wrong with the world. You
don't made everything else sin but the
law.
Hooking and drinking
>> Exactly. And if you want some good rap
music, check out IOG Houston Truth Bars.
All they do is rap uh bi- uh
scriptures.
>> That's it. As long as they don't break
the law
ain't nothing wrong with music. You want
to hear rap music? You want to hear some
jazz, rock and roll, whatever but as
long as you don't do it on the Lord's
Sabbath day.
>> That's right.
Yeah. Yeah.
When you see me with my headphones on,
I'm doing a little jamming under there
myself.
>> Right. See, because one of the big
problem is
you take everything away from people
that they can do all and something at
the some pleasures that you can't do can
do
and then uh uh
you get one pe- one side don't even want
to deal with the word of God cuz you
can't do nothing.
And then again, too,
and the people that
make everything else sin, they don't
keep the law.
>> Right.
>> So, sin is a transgression of the law.
Anything else you can find pleasure in
as long as it don't
break the law, you're not in violation.
>> All right.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right, we're going to move on to our
next question.
>> Uh next one, LaTia Lewis asks,
"Is it an image or idol
if a shirt has written on it, Jesus is
king?"
>> Well, I mean, no.
>> No, it's it it is
uh
The Lord with Somebody go and read the
go to
20th chapter
of Exodus and start reading.
In verse one.
>> And God spake all these words, saying,
"I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make unto thee any graven
image,
or any likeness of anything that is in
heaven above, or that is in the earth
beneath, or that is in the water under
the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them, for I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children to the
third and fourth generation of them that
hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands
>> Now, it said, "Don't make no image or
anything about own and worship it."
Now, if you got the name of Jesus on
your t-shirt or sweat, you are not
worship you know, what you doing is
advertising your God.
>> That's right.
>> Ain't no violation in that.
If you make a stance If you make your
stance here of a cow,
a monkey, or snake,
and you said that this is my God, then
you having some other God before him.
But, if you said Jesus your God and your
king, then you ain't having no other God
before
him. You acknowledging him.
>> That's right.
Yes, indeed, cuz he is the king of king
and the lord of lords. Could we uh could
we go to Revelation 19
>> Go ahead.
>> Revelation 19 and verse one verse verse
16.
Read it, Tenzel.
>> And he have on his vesture and on his
thigh a name written,
king of kings
and lord of lords.
>> That's what Jesus got on his garment
when he come.
>> Yep. And
that's right. He is indeed all that and
so much more.
>> Right.
>> All right. We're going to leave that
there as we continue to keep moving,
sisters. Time is ticking.
>> Yes, Sky Rider says, "I heard Pastor
Bully say or said that cherubims have
six wings, but don't the scriptures
teach that cherubims have four wings and
seraphims have six wings. And Ezekiel
1:6
and Isaiah 6:2
are given."
>> 6 and verse two.
>> Yes, Ezekiel 1 verse 6 and Isaiah 6
verse 2.
>> Let's go to that that Ezekiel 1.
And verse 6. Can you read it there?
And when you get there
I want you to go ahead and read it and
then we're going to ask the uh
You guys call her to represent that
question.
Go ahead, my brother.
>> And everyone had four faces and everyone
had four wings.
>> Now, I want you to keep reading. Say uh
cuz they're going to tell you how many
wings he did what with those wings.
>> And their feet were
And their
And their feet were straight feet and
the soles of their feet was like the
soles of a calf's foot and they sparkled
like the color of
burnished brass.
They had the hands of a man under their
wings on their four sides and they four
had their faces and their wings.
Their wings were joined one to another.
They turned not when they went.
They went everyone straight forward.
As for the likeness of their faces, they
four had the faces of a man, the face of
a lion on the right side and they
and on the right side and on and they
four had the faces of an ox on the left
side, they four also had the face of an
eagle.
Thus were their faces and their wings
were stretched upward.
Two wings of everyone
were joined one to another
and two covered their bodies.
>> Now, let's do a count.
They had two wings that were stretched
upward.
>> Yeah.
>> Then you have two that were joined one
to another.
>> Yeah.
>> They had two that covered their bodies.
>> Right.
>> That's six wings. The four is a typo. In
fact, you had other typos in there. Keep
reading. Let me show you about that.
>> Give me.
Okay.
>> And they went everyone straight forward
whether the spirit was to go they went
and they turned out
when they went. And as for the likeness
of the living creatures, their
appearance was like burning coals of
fire and like the appearance of flame
it went up and down among the living
creatures and the fire was bright and
out of the fire went forth lightning.
And the living creatures ran and
returned as the appearance of a flash of
lightning.
Now as I beheld the living creatures,
behold one wheel upon the earth by the
living creatures with his four faces.
Their appearance of the wheel and their
work was like unto the color of a beryl.
And they four had one likeness and their
appearance and their work was as it were
a wheel in the middle of a wheel.
And when they went, they went upon their
four sides and they turned not when they
went.
As for their rings
they were so high that they were
dreadful. And their rings
>> What you mean as for their rings?
>> It's wings.
>> There you go. It's a typo, isn't it? Go
ahead.
>> Typo.
>> And their rings were full of eyes round
about their four.
Right about them four.
>> Right. They're not They're They're So
but these were around the Lord. But they
were and seraphim
is
a uh uh
a misspelling. When you go to seraphim,
you know why?
Go to uh uh
uh
Exodus
the third chapter
and let's see
who was it that protected the uh
tree of life.
That's 3 20 and 20 to
to 22.
22 to 24.
>> You want Genesis?
>> Yeah.
Genesis 3:22 to 24.
Okay.
And the Lord said, "Behold, the man is
become one of us to know good and evil.
And now, lest he put forth his hand and
take also of the tree of life and eat
and live forever."
Therefore, the Lord God sent him forth
from the garden of Eden to till the
ground from whence he was taken.
So, he drove out the man and he placed
at the east of the garden of Eden
cherubims
and a flaming sword which turned every
way to keep the way of the tree of life.
>> Okay. So, the tree of life is Jesus. So,
what did he put around cherub angels,
didn't he?
>> Right.
>> Let's go to his
his where his kingdom is here and and to
his throne. Let's go in the Revelation
the fourth chapter and start reading
that verse.
>> Revelation 4:1.
>> After this, I looked and behold,
a door was open in heaven.
And the first voice which I heard was as
it were a trumpet
talking with me which said, "Come up
hither and I will show thee things which
must be hereafter."
>> He didn't say, "I will show you what's
in heaven." He said, "I'm going to show
you things which must be hereafter." Go
ahead.
>> And immediately I I was in the spirit
and behold, a throne was set in heaven,
and one sat on the throne.
And he that sat was to look upon like a
jasper
and sardine stone. And there was a
rainbow round about the throne and sight
like into an emerald.
And round about the throne were four and
twenty seats. Upon the seats I saw four
and twenty elders sitting clothed in
white raiment. And they had on their
heads crowns of gold.
And out of the throne proceeded light
and thunder and voices. And there were
seven lamps of burnt fire a fire burning
before the throne, which are the seven
spirits of God.
And before the throne there was a sea of
glass like unto a crystal.
And in the midst of the throne and round
about the throne were four beasts full
of eyes before and behind.
>> Full of eyes.
And the first beast was like a lion.
And the second beast like a calf.
And the third beast had a face of a man.
And the fourth beast
was like a flying eagle.
And the four beasts
>> Now here John, actually all four of them
had the same faces. But it's four, isn't
it?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Look at the faces. They're the same ones
as in Ezekiel. But go ahead and read.
>> And the four beasts
had each of them six wings about him.
And they were full of eyes within and
they rest not day and night saying,
"Holy, holy, holy, Lord God almighty,
which was and is
and is to come."
>> Yes, sir.
>> So how many wings did they have each?
>> Six wings.
>> See, you have to know what you're
looking at when you read the book. First
thing is the Lord put cherub angels
around him in in Genesis the third
chapter to keep man away. And every time
you go in there and when they build the
Tabernacle of the congregation of the
temple, they put in the ark of the
covenant. On top of the ark of the
covenant, they put in the mercy seat.
And on each line and of the mercies
around the mercy seat, they put in
cherub angels.
So, it says seraphims, it should have
been cherubims.
>> Yes.
>> So, the the same angels that's been
around him since the time when Adam and
Eve sinned, and they still going to be
around him when he set his kingdom up.
Each one of them have six wings.
>> So, when you see that So, when you see
that four, it should be six. That's a
typo.
>> That's it.
>> Yeah.
And and even that we didn't go there in
question that Isaiah 6 and verse 2, it
says too that they had six wings.
>> Yes.
>> Right.
>> Yeah. So.
>> Right. Might have called them seraphim.
Ain't no seraphim, it's cherubims.
>> Yeah.
>> Same angels.
>> All right.
So, we thank you for that question,
Sister Deborah. Time check.
>> Yes, the time is 9:04.
>> Uh, we have ran over, but we have
enjoyed ourselves. We thank you all from
all around the world who sent in those
questions. And we want to say if you
submitted a question and we didn't have
a chance to get to it, please don't
resubmit it. Sister Deborah, take it,
put it in rotation, and we will deal
with that question next week. So, until
we all come together again, we ask that
you be safe,
be blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as Brother
Tenzel closes us out.
>> Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil. For thine is the
kingdom, and the power, and the glory
forever. In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.